I am famous high school
student detective,  Kudo Shinichi.
One day when I went with my childhood
friend Ran to an amusement park...
...I witnessed a scene of some men
in black involved in some suspicious deal.
And then one of those men
made me take a drug.
When I woke up,
my body had been shrunken.
If they knew that Kudo
Shinichi was still alive...
...they would bring harm
to all those around me.
Naming myself Edogawa Conan, I look for
information on the Black Organization.
The people who know my true identity are...
Professor Agasa and my
classmate Haibara Ai.
Her real name is Miyano Shiho.
Her codename in
the Black Organization is Sherry.
She developed the drug known as
Apoptoxin 4869 which made me small.
In order to escape the organization
after they had killed her sister...
...she took the drug herself.
And became Haibara Ai.
She is now researching an antidote.
But we only know that Apoptoxin 4869
can be suppressed with alcohol compounds...
...returning our bodies to
their original form momentarily.
I may be small but
my intellect is still as it was.
There is always one truth!
And this is the latest story.
“Black Organization- Gin”
It stinks.
“Black Organization- Vodka”
It stinks?
It reeks of the scent of
the woman who betrayed us.
I have a feeling that
we’ll meet her tonight.
Sherry...you.
Wow...What a beautiful hotel!
“Edogawa Conan”
Nice...There must be plenty of
famous people staying here.
You can feel the presence of
Suzuki Conglomerate here, right?
This is a splendid hotel, right? Ai?
“Haibara Ai”
“Ah! I want to stay here with Shinichi”
Weren’t you thinking about it?
No, I wasn’t...I was only thinking
of staying with Conan.
-Was it right, Conan?
-Eh...Yeah.
They are both the same person though.
It’s a million years too early
for this brat to be living in this hotel.
That Sonoko...
Oh? Where is Uncle Kogoro?
About that…
“Detective Mori Kogoro”
What? What? What?
You can meet Miss Japanesque?!
“Miss Japanesque Kotobuki Karen”
Karen. You’re beautiful.
Where? Where? Where? Where?
Where is it?
The new hotel which belongs to Sonoko.
They said the party is being broadcasted
live and attended by famous people.
I see.
When it comes to famous people…
Then I, Mori Kogoro who
has solved many cases in the past.
Hey. Hey.
I was the one who solved them all.
It can’t be helped...I’ll have to go then.
I’ll go change into my tuxedo.
Wait dad!
It isn’t my fault if Karen falls for me.
No. No. I want to meet her.
I want to meet Karen.
And so. He fell down
the stairs and broke his leg.
No. No!
Karen…I need to meet her.
He must be resting in
the hospital right now.
And so...Ai and I are taking his place.
We didn’t have time to change.
-Is it alright if we came dressed like this?
-It’ll be fine.
You look cute in anything you wear.
Let's go.
Why did you have to come?
Don’t you know?
For a woman, she needs to look at
other women to improve herself.
Huh?
-Sonoko.
-We’ll be in your hands for today.
This is Mimi, Miss Japanesque,
Karen’s sister.
“Karen’s sister, Kotobuki Mimi”
My sister had received
a letter threatening her.
“My precious Karen…”
“Congratulations on receiving the award”
“Tonight, I will strike your heart…”
“And make you my puppet”
“Disobey me and you will DIE”
I was under the door just now.
I have informed
several members of the staff.
It smells sweet.
That’s dangerous.
-Let’s call the police immediately.
-That’s unnecessary.
Look.
Let him come at me if he wants to.
I have worked so hard
to become Miss Japanesque.
I won’t lose to a coward like this.
-Did you just put in 10 times too much?
-I’m sorry.
It may taste strange but it isn’t bad.
-Just serve them as it is.
-Yes.
-Here you go.
-Oh. It looks delicious.
Here. Cake for the children.
Even so, Karen must be a strong woman.
But we don’t even know
which weirdo wrote that letter.
Ran, go call
your husband, Shinichi Kudo.
Eh!
Ran...Please!
Okay.
It’s his mailbox again…
Shinichi...Miss Japanesque, Karen
had received a threatening letter.
If you can come…
Your precious Ran is in trouble.
Come to Bell Hotel immediately. |
Got it?
Sonoko...Shinichi is
very busy, you know?
If he doesn’t come because of this,
just dump him already!
That man’s been missing
since forever.
What will you do?
You can give her a call,
you know...
You’re right.
Kudo.
Haibara...
That cake...
Yes. That taste…
The one you were made to drink…
Baigar wine...it’s probably in the liquor.
Haibara...hurry.
My body feels hot.
It’s returning back to original form.
Are you alright? Haibara...
Sorry for having you break
into the girls’ changing room.
What will we do now?
If we transform back
into our original bodies.
Haibara!
Very well.
We’ll go with that, please.
Hello there.
Nice to meet you.
I’m wearing white, you see.
You go and change.
Didn’t you say that
you were wearing black?
The colour of the stage lights
made me change my mind.
Hurry on now.
"Runner-up Kyoumi Kawada"
Take this off.
My tiara wouldn’t stand out.
This is my mother’s momento.
I will never take this off.
Karen, can you stop this already?
Mr Miura.
You are the head of judges, right?
Remove her from the list of runner-ups.
Please.
Can you take that off?
Karen says that she wants
to stand closer to the front.
She just wants
to stand out by herself.
"Stage Director Shoichi Amano"
We’ve another 10 minutes.
Hurry and tell them
to change the lighting.
Suzuki Conglomerate,
commemorating the opening of Bell Hotel…
Will now begin the
Miss Japanesque Awards Ceremony.
Conan and Ai are late…
They are just playing around like kids.
And now...two of the
Miss Japanesque runner-ups.
Sumika Abe and Kyoumi Kawada.
Thank you for waiting.
And now, this year’s Miss Japanesque,
Kotobuki Karen!
More tightly, Camera 3!
Today is a day of beginning for me.
I will definitely get
top spot in the world pageant.
I believe that it is my duty to promote
the beauty of Japan to the world.
From the bottom of my heart,
I wish to thank the people involved...
Yes, this is Agasa.
Shinichi?
Trust me...I’ll come for you now.
Professor?
It’s Ai. She and Conan are lost
and I have to look for them.
-Then, I’ll come…
-I’ll be fine. Stay here, Ran.
Are you really Ai?
Can you stop staring at me
like that, professor?
No, I actually know about it.
But to see it with my eyes...
It feels like “please to meet you”...
Then, “it’s been a while” for me, right?
Shinichi…
You’re great help, professor.
I almost had to crossdress.
That’s bad...
I wanted to see you crossdress.
-It’ll look good on you, definitely.
-Shut up.
That aside...what is going on, Shinichi?
It’s just like that time...
...when I accidentally drank
that wine in Baigar Province.
I was able to return
to my original form...
...thanks to the effects of
the wine’s compounds.
That aside, we shouldn’t let Haibara
appear in front of many people.
Now that she’s become like this.
Take her back
to your place immediately.
But Shinichi, wouldn’t that
be the same for you?
I can’t go back yet.
Are you going to see
your precious girlfriend?
Fool.
It’s that threatening letter.
I’ll stay here until the party safely ends.
We don’t know how long the effects
of the liquor in that cake will last.
There’s no telling of when
you’ll revert back to being a child.
I know.
-If that’s so…
-No matter how dangerous it may be…
It’s my nature as a detective...
...not to run away
from a case in front of me.
Take care of Haibara for me.
My disguise.
See you.
Well then, let's go.
First of all. Karen…
How did you feel after winning?
For the first 30 minutes,
Miss Japanesque will be on the stage.
At that time, I will check
the layout of the hotel.
For anything suspicious.
Kotobuki Karen’s personal room
on the 20th floor is locked.
In front is the head of judges’ room.
What a simple human relationship.
On the 10th floor are
the rooms of the runner-ups.
Only staff members with
a pass can enter the stage.
If the threatening letter was real...
...where would the criminal attack from?
Let’s give another round of
applause for Miss Japanesque.
Finally, Miss Japanesque, Kotobuki Karen
will give a piano performance.
Excuse me.
Would you like a drink?
He’s nice.
-Ah, juice please…
-Juice.
-How about you, Ran?
-I’m fine.
Conan and the others aren’t
back yet. I’ll go look for them.
I guess that we’ve hit
the jackpot with this dress.
If you do as I say, I will definitely
make you the world’s No.1.
That’s delightful.
Karen.
Why did you change
the contents of your speech?
Please do as I tell you.
You’re so noisy.
Don’t order me around just
because you’re my older sister.
I’m letting you be
my manager out of pity.
Karen. Please be
at standby at 8.45pm.
I know that already.
She acts like the queen, but
she couldn’t do anything by herself.
She’s just like a puppet.
Puppet?
“Puppet”
Just like that threatening letter,
I hope that she suffers...
Kyoumi.
You also feel that way, Amano, right?
Like how many times she asked
for changes in the rehearsal.
I’m just doing my job.
The elevator’s here.
Conan?
Ai?
Professor…
Conan?
Ai?
Shinichi!
Are you...Shinichi?
I can tell by just looking at your hand.
Yes.
It’s me.
Shinichi.
I’ve finally found you.
Finally…
Fool...don’t cry.
Where have you been all along?
I’ve been so worried.
I wanted to see you.
Ran.
Eh?
You’ve gained weight...
...since we last met.
That’s not good.
Now that you’ve said it.
My waist has recently…
Is that something you say
after not seeing me for so long?
Unbelievable.
That’s so like you.
Well. I forgive you.
Since you heard
my voice message, right?
Yes. And...I’m investigating
the hotel now.
That said, why are you
wandering around?
Conan and his friend, Ai are lost.
Oh, If it’s about those brats...
...the professor took them
home just now.
Is that so?
Then...
I’ll go investigate with you.
Eh?
How old are you?
-Sorry. But I’m working now.
-Do you have a girlfriend?
Karen.
Are you there? Answer me.
-What is this ruckus about?
-Don’t act dumb.
You’ve taken my sister
somewhere, right?
Karen always says...
I’ll suffocate whenever
I’m with my gloomy sister.
What did you say?
What’s wrong?
You are?
-Detectives.
-Detectives?
I am Mori Kogoro’s assistant.
Yes. We’re really my dad’s assistants.
Is Karen missing?
-This man’s taken her somewhere.
-I told you that I don’t know anything.
That’s right.
Let the detectives
prove my innocence.
Please.
She’s not in the room.
Can we examine
Karen’s room just in case?
Feel free to do so.
Ran, check the bathroom.
She’s not there.
-When was Karen missing?
-A little while ago.
She took a shower
after changing from her dress…
When I wasn’t looking.
-What dress would she be wearing next?
-It’s gone.
-Together with belt for the dress.
-The belt for the dress?
Karen will...in the end, rise up like
an angel from the stage basement.
For that to happen,
she need that belt…
In any case, I’m going to look for
my sister before the performance.
That poor thing…
With that meddling sister,
Karen’s nothing more than a puppet.
A puppet?
But she’s a professional.
She will be there for the performance.
There’s no cause for alarm.
What will you do, Shinichi?
We’ll look for Karen.
Ran, go look at the ballroom.
I cannot let people see me.
I understand.
Karen?
I haven’t seen her.
Thank you.
-Where’s Karen?
-I haven’t found her yet.
-Where’s this place?
-The stage basement.
Karen will use this pulley, and
ascend to the stage from here.
The head judge thought of it.
Miura only thinks of
controlling my sister.
I have to protect her.
Controlling her...?
Is Karen not with you?
She didn’t come at all?
It’s her usual selfishness again.
Another 15 minutes
till the performance.
She’ll probably appear
at the last minute.
I’ll go there.
You can look there.
What’s his problem?
He can at least tell me his age.
Karen is on standby
at the stage basement.
She’s finally here.
Yes. Yes.
Thank goodness.
Sorry for the trouble.
I’m counting on you.
That was stage director, Amano.
She’s on standby.
She’s probably harassing me.
Thank you for helping look for her.
Well then...
Thank you for waiting.
Miss Japanesque.
Karen Kotobuki’s piano recital!
You are late.
A little.
What’s that?
That’s not part of the performance.
-Did you do this?
-I don’t know.
-That’s disgusting.
-She’s like a real puppet.
What’s going on?
She’s dead...
Cut the cameras!
Switch to commercials!
Commercials!
Professor.
Sorry, Shinichi.
While I looked away...Ai…
Listen. Don’t let anyone out
no matter what. Got it?
No. Nobody may leave.
-No!~
-Shinichi?
Why did you come back?
To retrieve that cake.
If I analyse the contents,
then perhaps…
-What are you doing?
-It’s a live broadcast on television.
The viewership of this event
is likely about 20%.
There’s a one out of 5 chance that...
...the Black Organization
will learn of your whereabouts.
In any case, get out of here
as soon as you can.
No.
I can’t let this chance slip away.
How long do you plan to stay as a kid?
Don’t you want to return
to being Shinichi Kudo?
Shinichi...
What are you doing?
That’s none of your business.
Wait!
What did you mean by that?
Did you know how long
Ran had been waiting for you?
And then you finally turn up
with another woman.
Help. Somebody help me!
Anyways, there’s no time
for explanations.
Understood?
Hurry and get out of here.
What’s with him?
She...looks like someone.
I missed you...Sherry.
As usual, keep my involvement
in this investigation a secret.
I wouldn’t mind if you said so.
The criminal tied the victim’s limbs
and waist with strings.
The strings were cut and…she fell.
She was stabbed to death.
Yes. Most likely.
The victim had received
a threatening letter beforehand.
This knife...she carried it
around for self defense.
Inspector.
The threatening letter.
Tonight, I will strike your heart,
And make you my puppet.
Her body was hung up just like a puppet.
“I will strike your heart…”
means that...
...she got stabbed in
the heart with a knife.
This murder happened
just as the letter stated.
Based on the report
from forensics...
...the time of death is said to be
in between 8.30pm to 9pm.
She wasn’t in the stage
basement at around 8.45pm.
Excuse me Inspector.
I’ve brought him here.
You were the last person
to see the victim alive, correct?
Yes! It was 3 minutes
before the performance.
From the top of the stage.
Karen, the performance
will start soon.
Are you ready?
You started the performance
without her responding?
It’s not unusual that
Karen doesn’t respond.
Who would think that she’s dead?
The time of the murder was...
...between 8.45pm to 8.57pm.
In a 12-minute timespan.
And the person without an alibi within
this timespan would be the criminal.
Even so, that is
a terrible way of killing someone.
Excuse me.
-Yes.
-Shinichi?
Yes.
Ai wouldn’t go home with me.
Haibara.
Even when we ate different amounts.
The symptoms appeared
at the same time.
Gender difference
may have been a factor.
I need a sample no matter what.
Hurry and leave!
Even when you tell me that there’s
a 1 in 5 chance that I’ll be in danger…
There’s a 4 out of 5 chance
that I’ll be safe.
We’re in this together.
We escape together…
And investigate together.
There’s no other way.
-Ran.
-Sorry.
The professor has the car ready
and told me to call you.
Haibara.
Ran.
I’ll explain it later.
It’s an emergency.
I’m sorry, but could you
take her to the professor?
Please.
I understand.
Can I at least...have your name?
You don’t have to…
You have your reasons, right?
-Her name is...Hai...
-Hairi.
I’m half Japanese.
Please to meet you.
I’m Ran Mori.
Hmm...
Have I seen you before?
It’s like I’ve known you from somewhere.
Really?
I’ve never met you before.
I guess so.
Well then, see you later...Shinichi.
The professor’s car is that way.
Let’s go.
What's wrong?
Who was that man?
Professor.
You’re still here…
Someone was going to
attack Hairi with a knife.
She protected me.
Come here.
It’s them?
We’re already surrounded.
I can’t let them see the professor
and her, together with us.
And involve the two in our mess.
By losing your knife,
you lose your life.
So...what do we do now?
They are trapped here.
There’s no need to hurry.
It would be fun to corner them slowly.
I see you, Sherry...
Your back shivering in fear.
Haibara.
I feel them.
Their presence.
They are near.
Who is she?
You know her, professor?
I’ve heard that he uses an assistant.
That must be her.
He has an assistant. Yet he hasn’t
told me anything about her.
And...
He was talking to her with such
an expression in his face.
It’s the first time
I’ve seen his face like that.
It’s like Shinichi has became
a stranger to me.
Shinichi is Shinichi, no matter what.
He hasn’t changed.
What would he do
if you do not trust him?
I am already under
the organization’s crosshairs.
All that’s left is for them to pull the trigger.
It’s not like you to be all weak like that.
At least, you’ll be safe with the police around.
After that, I’ll protect you…
You...
...and also Ran.
Can I ask for something?
If I am close to danger,
don’t hesitate to leave me behind.
Fool. Are you sleeptalking?
A detective never
gets rid of his evidence...
...even if it gets in
the way of his reasoning.
I’ll add it into my reasoning and
hold unto it until I solve the case.
Rest assured.
Kudo.
There are no fingerprints
on the knife...
And we’ve gathered
everyone without an alibi.
Understood.
Who is this lady?
Ah...! She’s my assistant.
Then, from 8.45pm to 3 minutes
before the performance.
Between those 12 minutes.
Please tell us where and what
you were doing at that time.
Starting with you.
I was looking for my sister.
And who can verify that?
You were Karen’s manager…
But I heard that your relationship
with her was bad.
That was for her own good.
-You...
-I was in my room all along.
I had a phone call
with a business partner.
You can confirm it with him.
It’s possible that
he’s your accomplice.
That doesn’t count as an alibi.
And you are obsessed with Karen…
But she neglected you and
you hated her at the same time.
What did you say?
Runner-up Miss Japanesque,
Abe Sumika...
-Where were you?
-I was in Kyoumi’s room all along.
Both of you thought ill of Karen.
And should Karen disappear,
the person who gains the most is...
...either one of you runner-ups.
There’s a possibility that both of you
could have conspired to murder Karen.
Stage director, Shoichi Amano.
At 8.45pm, I was with
the both of them…
I went to the stage basement
to see if she was there.
And then I went to back
to tuning the equipment.
I went to check if she was in
the basement several times, but…
In other words…
Your alibi isn’t perfect.
Well. But why would I kill Karen?
Don’t underestimate the police.
You were her ex-lover.
You were both in the theatre group
and saw the same dream, but…
Now...look at how different
the two of you have become.
I was happy with her success.
That’s the truth.
Is she there?
No, not yet.
Not anywhere.
Get ready.
When the cops pull out,
that is when...
...the hunt begins.
What is this feeling?
There’s something different
from when I came in before.
And there is another
thing that feels off.
And I will make you my puppet...
Was it your idea?
Like a puppet.
What’s going on?
There’s still something
I don’t understand.
Take a look at this.
This bloodtrail continues from
the entrance to the pulley.
Inspector Megure.
Please confirm whether
this is the victim’s blood.
Alright.
If this bloodstain is hers…
She may have been murdered
elsewhere and then moved here.
Why go through all that trouble?
The first explanation is that...
...it is too risky for
the criminal to kill her here.
There’s no telling when a staff,
looking for Karen would appear.
That said…
He could have killed her in another
location and brought her here...
...for the sake of the puppet show
over a short period of time.
The second explanation?
To hide the true murder scene.
What's wrong?
Nothing…
Something’s wrong.
Let’s go.
Here’s the key to Karen’s room.
What about the keys
to the other rooms?
The rooms that were rented out,
were to Miura, Sumika and Kyoumi.
The other keys are strictly
managed by the hotel.
I see. Thank you.
What was that?
It can’t be helped.
Shinichi cannot see anything else
when he’s on a case,
Ran…
Kindness is not just about being able
to understand others’ feelings.
You also need to learn
when to be selfish.
I’ll be fine.
When the case is over,
I’ll talk to Shinichi properly.
Please do not worry.
I understand. Let’s go.
But what was that about?
Just now...
Haibara.
Don’t wander around
the hotel by yourself.
Is it the time to be
worrying about me?
She’s suffering with me around.
She’s doing her best
to act as it isn’t.
You know that, right?
I don’t know how long
I’ll remain like this.
Being kind to her now, only
makes separating more painful.
What happens when
we return to a kid’s body?
What if I cannot find a cure?
Will we be classmates forever?
Will we be able to
live normally forever?
Forever…
Haibara?
It’ll be fine.
If we don’t find the cure,
after 10 years, you’ll be 17.
And Ran will be 27.
Both of you will no longer
be children by then.
I bet that you two will overcome
the age gap and fall in love.
So don’t worry.
Fool!
How would you know
what would happen by then?
I wouldn’t know but
I’m not giving up on hope.
I’ll definitely get my body back...
...and destroy those
Black Organization bastards.
You want to avenge
your sister too, right?
You’re right.
The criminal hung the body,
even when it put him at risk.
What is it?
What bothers me?
Damn...
At a time like this.
I’ve borrowed it.
The footage from just now.
Let’s see it.
This is it.
That has been bothering me.
But at that time, the five...
Kudo?
I see.
That is probably why
the criminal did that to the body.
On top of that…
I now understand the other thing
that was bothering me.
But there was another thing
which I didn’t understand.
Damn!
I’m running out of time.
Shinichi.
-What’s wrong?
-Nothing.
How can it be nothing?
Why?
Why wouldn’t you tell me?
Ran.
I cannot turn back
into Conan in front of Ran.
I need to do something
and solve this case.
I know who the criminal is.
Gather everyone.
Shinichi.
I understand.
I’ll go.
Until you tell me everything,
I’ll wait for you.
Because I believe in you.
Ran.
It’s over once you
transform in front of her.
Yeah.
That is why I need
to settle the case now.
You know the criminal?
Really?
Yes.
The criminal who hung
the body on the stage...
...wanted to show off
the murder in a reckless way.
This murder happened just as
it was written in the threatening letter.
Smell this.
-This.
-Yes.
The smell of a cigar.
This threatening letter has...
...the special sweet smell
of the cigar you smoke.
Daigo Miura.
Eh? No way.
Unbelievable.
You may not notice
since you’re the smoker...
...and your nose
is used to the smell.
It was me.
Once she became
Miss Japanesque...
...Karen began to distance
herself from me.
She had only been using me.
But I wrote that!
I didn’t kill her!
Explain yourself
at the police station.
Inspector Megure.
Daigo Miura.
You are under arrest for
the murder of Kotobuki Karen.
Wait. I didn’t kill her.
It’s true.
It wasn’t me! Hey. wait!
-Don’t touch me with your dirty hands!
-Hurry and get in!
Thank goodness.
They’ve caught the criminal.
Is that true?
Oh?
Where’s Shinichi?
As I expected…
You are the true criminal...
Amano Shouichi.
What do you mean by that?
Wasn’t the criminal, Miura?
That was a feint to root
you out as the true criminal.
Why would I?
I only have a few minutes
without an alibi.
If the place of murder was here,
it’s possible that you’re the criminal.
Karen was murdered here
and you were in trouble.
I’ve thought of 2 reasons
why you would hang the body.
First reason...
To match the murder
with the threatening letter.
Leading everyone to believe that the
person who wrote the letter is the criminal.
And the other reason is…
To hide the real method
behind the murder.
The real method?
Your goal was not to hang the body.
But to drop the body.
To hide the fact that the victim
had been beaten to death.
had been beaten to death?
Stop here.
This was the first part
which doubted me.
Zoom in here.
A part of hair is stuck to the head
and wasn’t dangling downwards.
Yes it is. Why?
It’s a bloodstain.
There was a wound here...
...and the blood dried
making the hair stick at this part.
That’s why a part of her hair
wasn’t dangling downwards.
If something falls...
...and there’s a crack.
People would assume that the crack
had been caused by the fall just now.
But that crack was caused
before the fall.
You used this illusion to hide the fact
that the victim had been beaten to death.
Well, once forensics
examine the injury...
...they will learn whether the wound
had been caused before or after her death.
You had no such knowledge.
The wound is located
on the left side of the head.
If the victim had been beaten
to death from behind...
What was that for!?
The criminal is left handed.
And you’ve just used your left hand.
On the other hand, all the other
suspects were right handed.
That’s messed up.
You were forced to use
your right hand, right?
But unknowingly, you would use
your left hand on reflex.
Like just now.
Just to be accused
as the criminal like that?
You said that blood dried up
on Karen’s hair, right?
That means Karen was killed
long before the performance started.
I was always with the staff here.
And at 8.45pm, Mimi and I were looking for her here.
She was nowhere to be found by then.
-Correct?
-Yes.
If you say that I killed Karen here,
then where would her body be?
It was here.
We just couldn’t see it.
When looking for Karen
after the incident happened.
I came here and
had my second doubt.
That is...
...this amount of paint.
-She didn’t come at all?
-It’s her usual selfishness again.
At that time,
there were 3 rows of paint.
But now 2 rows.
What do you mean?
They were moved back
to their original place.
Here.
Then what?
You removed the paint in this box...
...and temporarily placed
Karen’s body in here.
A person wouldn’t fit in
such a small box.
Among these 3 cardboard boxes,
You move the middle one a little
further behind, to form a zig-zag.
That is why we never thought
that they contained a body.
When you arrange
the body in a “ku” curved shape,..
...the body will be hidden.
You left Karen’s body
in a “ku” curved shape,
You took out the paint, and
covered the body with the boxes.
It’s here.
Karen’s blood.
If you says so, then
show me concrete evidence!
Concrete evidence
that says that I killed her!
There’s one thing which
I didn’t know about earlier.
The murder weapon
used to kill Karen.
You shouldn’t have enough
time to dispose of it.
But I do not know where you hid it.
That is why I had Miura arrested…
...to assure the true criminal
that it was safe.
I felt that he would definitely
return to the place...
...where he hid the murder
weapon to dispose it.
And you fell for it.
This is the concrete evidence.
I didn’t mean to kill her.
But...
-What do you want?
-Nothing.
-Just wanted to congratulate you.
-Lies!
Weren’t you the one
who sent that letter?
You were just jealous
because I was successful, right?
Karen…
You and I loved each other.
-And you still don’t believe me?
-I don’t believe you!
Don’t get cocky.
The time I spent with you is nothing
but rubbish to me now.
No. Worse than rubbish!
To think that
I’ve dated you disgusts me...
...and makes me want to run away.
Can you get out of my sight?
Forever!
We really believed in
one another back then.
Even so...
Would such feelings become nothing
more than lies after we separated?
Shoichi Amano.
You are under arrest for
the murder of Kotobuki Karen.
Thank you for your assistance tonight.
Shinichi, are you alright?
Yes.
Aside from that, I need you to
put her into protective custody.
-Damn.
-Shinichi?
-Inspector, we are ready to go.
-I’ll be there.
That idiot. All by herself…
If I examine all of these…
I’m an idiot.
I know that I don’t have much time.
Even if I was prepared for this.
Impossible.
Already?
Are you trying to act cool?
Why?
I’m a detective.
Shinichi.
It’s not what you think.
I was targeted and scared.
Targeted?
Aren’t you Shinichi’s assistant?
-Ah...no…
-You're right.
I’m not his assistant.
I’m a client asked him
to investigate a case for me.
A client?
Thanks to him the criminal
had been apprehended but...
...the criminal’s associates who have
grudges, have come into this hotel.
He was only trying to protect me.
Well? Do you believe me?
Yes.
Anyway, let’s get out of here.
We’ll talk later.
Shinichi! Are you alright?
You're strange.
Sorry. A slight fever.
Which one?
Up or down?
Where should I go?
I have talked to dad
about our situation just now.
He said that he’s coming to
the rooftop on a police helicopter.
You're fool!
If they do that, they’ll be…
Wait.
That’s a good idea!
Kudo?
It’s the time limit.
What do you mean?
Get in quick!
Shinichi, hurry!
Sorry, Ran...
Shinichi?
Kudo?
I can’t transform into Conan
in front of Ran.
Get in quick!
-They're here.
-Hurry up.
If the elevator moves,
they’ll come after us.
-I’ll stay behind and become bait.
-No!
-We’ll leave together.
-Don’t worry.
I...
I can’t die yet.
But if I do...
...please tell Ran that...
I will been always by her side.
Always by her side.
I won’t do that.
I believe that I’ll see you again.
Take care of Ran.
Haibara.
Kudo.
See you later.
That’s a man, Gin.
Yes. I don’t know who he is but…
Sherry seems to have
a knight in shining armor.
But where is she?
If we display his dead body...
...Sherry will give herself out.
I need to buy time
for them to escape.
I need to play hide and seek
until they do.
Where did he go?
Damn.
Is the helicopter there yet?
What am I doing?
Of course it’ll be locked.
My brain can't function properly.
This...is the victim’s room key.
They should have reached
the roof by now.
It’s now or never.
Gin.
The knight is on the 20th floor.
Which room should we search?
All of them.
He’s not here.
It has to be this room.
Alright.
Give up,  Mr.Knight.
There’s nowhere else
for you to run.
Surrender and get on your
knees in front of my gun!
-I wonder about that...
-What?
Damn. No lights.
Can you hear this sound?
I called them.
It’s the sound of 20 helicopters
from the police SWAT team.
What?
They’re over there!
I’m coming for you, Ran!
What?!
According to Ran, there should be
Ran, the boy detective and his client.
Isn’t that the professor’s kid?
The detective brother is being
chased down by bad men.
Save him! Hurry!
Boy Detective?
Where! Where is he?
Soon, there’ll be about 50 officers
rushing down towards here.
You guys should be
the ones surrendering.
-Gin.
-Don’t buy into it.
It’s a bluff.
If that were true...
...they should have come here directly
when we heard the helicopter sounds.
That’s most likely...
...the TV station’s helicopter...
...which came to film the party.
There you are.
What are you?
You...?
A detective.
There he is! Boy detective!
It’s the cops!
-Boy detective!
-Kudo!
Ran, do you recognize me?
Dad?
Thank goodness.
Ran!
You worried us.
Ai, why are you here?
She said that she got lost in the
building and ended up on the rooftop.
Hairi who was holding you...
...left you with Ai and
returned into the building.
She told Ai that a police helicopter
would arrive and everything would be fine.
I see…
Shinchi?
Where’s Shinichi?
-Kudo is on to another case…
-He’s dead.
Eh?
That good for nothing is dead.
He’s dead.
Impossible.
He was lying, right?
No. I can’t be.
I believed that he’ll come back.
I believed...
It’s ringing.
Your phone’s ringing.
Shinchi?
Shinchi, is that you?
You know it’s me.
Thank goodness.
You're alive.
Idiot. Idiot!
How?!
-That explosion just now…
-No way!
I’m fine. You don’t have
to call me an idiot.
Idiot. Idiot. Idiot....
You…
Hairi, is she safe?
Y...Yes...
She’s fine.
Her pursuers got spooked
by the police and ran.
I want to see you, Shinichi.
I want to see you now.
Sorry…
After I take her to somewhere safe,
I have another case.
I still have a lot to do.
Don’t worry.
I’ll come back someday...
...just to see your silly face.
The ”silly” part is unnecessary.
If the professor is there,
let me talk to him.
I have something to ask from him.
It's a call from Shinichi.
Hello...Hello?
You’re really lucky.
How did you survive?
I have to thank Suzuki Conglomerate
for building that laundry chute box.
Just before the explosion, I transformed
back into Conan and used it to escape.
I see.
And...can you bring me my kiddy
clothes? I have nothing to wear.
Sorry. But can you ask
the professor directly?
I don’t feel want to see you in the nude.
Hey! Haibara!
Don’t just snatch the phone
and hang up like that.
Think what I went through all
that trouble to save you.
There was only 1 police helicopter.
They must have after receiving
a report about a building robbery.
-That was a bluff after all.
-Yes.
I snooped around
the hotel again but...
...that woman was
nowhere to be found.
And that helicopter was gone too.
Even so, who was that man
whom he blew up?
A detective.
Could it be?
But dad, how did you know
which room Shinichi was in?
Well it is because of the Great Detective
Kogoro Mori’s great skills of reasoning.
How did you know?
That hotel used lighting
to form a message.
The “Suzu” word from
Suzuki Congromerate’s name...
But there was one room
without the lights on.
And that is the room where I thought
that detective boy was hiding.
Wow! As expected of dad.
Today, I’ll make whatever you like.
Well...Well...
Can I have 5 bottles of beer?
No, you can’t.
-I’m back.
-You're late.
Even after leaving early,
where were you?
The professor’s place. He bought
a new game and I was hooked unto it.
I see. I was worried.
Sister Ran.
Did something good happen?
I met Shinichi today.
-Brother Shinichi?
-Yes.
What a beautiful full moon.
Come, Conan.
Is Shinichi looking at it
from somewhere, too?
He probably tired
and sleeping by now.
I’m watching it with you...
Ran...